A Finding Aid to the Werner Drewes Papers, 1838-2015, bulk 1890-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.drewwern
Archives of American Art
- Artwork and Sketchbooks, circa 1890s-2002; Series 7; 3.67 Linear feet Boxes 6-9, 16-17
  - Sketchbook R7B: New England, 1968 September (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Sketchbook R8A: Untitled, circa 1940s (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sketchbook R8B: Life Drawings, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Sketchbooks R9 (2 books): Untitled and Life Drawings, circa 1940 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Sketchbooks R10 (2 books): Untitled and Life Drawings, circa 1940s (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Sketchbook R11: Life Drawings, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sketchbook R12: Figures, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Sketchbook R16: Untitled, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Sketchbook R17B: Yucatan and Figure, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 4
  - Sketchbook R18D: Untitled, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Sketchbook R19A: Luxemburg (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 5
  - Sketchbook R20 C: New England, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Sketchbook R22 C: Untitled, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Sketchbook R23C: Untitled, circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Sketchbook R24: Title Illegible, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Sketchbook R25B: France, Italy, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Sketchbook R26C: Untitled, circa 1956 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Sketchbook R27C: Untitled, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Sketchbook R31A: Europe, Yucatan, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Sketchbook R35B: Europe, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Sketchbook R36B: France, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Sketchbook R37B: Greece, Europe, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Sketchbook R38B: Holiday in Norway, Rhine River Trip etc., 1977 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Sketchbook R39B: Untitled, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Sketchbook R40B: Gandria, 1980 July 24 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Sketchbook R41B: Switzerland, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Sketchbook R42C: Untitled, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Loose Sketches R43: Abstract, 1941-1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Loose Sketches R45: Nature, 1930s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 3-6)
  - Loose Sketches R46: Black and White, Nature, 1930s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 7-11)
  - Loose Sketches R47: Abstracts, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 12-15)
  - Loose Sketches R49: NFS Abstracts, 1935-1946 (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
  - Loose Sketches R50: Abstracts, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 18-22)
  - Loose Sketches R51: Pages from Old Sketchbooks, 1937-1939 (Box 8, Folder 23-27)
  - Collage R55, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Handmade Booklet R56, circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Sketchbook R62: "From My Little Sketchbook, Remembrances of 1970: to Maria" (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Loose Sketches R65, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 31)
    Oversized material housed in Box 16, Folder 6
  - Cards Made for Mary (Maria) Louise Drewes R67, 1960-1980s (Box 8, Folder 32)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, Folder 1
  - Loose Sketches R72, 1930s-1940s (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Loose Sketches R73: Nature, Farm and St. Louis, 1934-1960 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Loose Sketches R75: Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, Folder 2
  - Loose Sketches Not Numbered: Abstracts, 1930s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - Loose Sketches Not Numbered: Abstracts, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Loose Sketches Not Numbered: Nature, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
  - Loose Sketches Not Numbered: Nature, 1940s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Loose Sketches Not Numbered: Old, Mounted, circa 1930s-circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 13-15)
  - Loose Sketches Not Numbered: Untitled, 1940s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, Folder 3
  - Loose Sketches Not Numbered: Untitled, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - Artwork by Others, circa 1915-2002 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, Folder 4
  - Artwork by Others, Family Members, circa 1890s (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Oversized Sketchbook R5A: Untitled (Mounted Sketches) from Box 7, Folder 4 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Sketchbook R12: Figures from Box 7, Folder 14 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Sketchbook R16: Untitled from Box 7, Folder 15 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Sketchbook R17B: Yucatan and Figure from Box 7, Folder 16 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Sketchbook R18D: Untitled from Box 7, Folder 17 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Sketchbook R19A: Luxemburg from Box 7, Folder 18 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Sketchbook R20 C: New England from Box 7, Folder 19 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Loose Sketches R65 from Box 8, Folder 31 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Cards Made for Mary (Maria) Louise Drewes R67 from Box 8, Folder 32 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Loose Sketches R75: Miscellaneous from Box 9, Folder 3 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Loose Sketches Not Numbered: Untitled from Box 9, folder 16 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Artwork by Others from Box 9, Folder 19 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Photographic Material, circa 1890s-2000; Series 8; 5.53 Linear feet Boxes 9-14, 17, MGP 2
  One series of photographis was labeled with black labels and numbered as the "BK" series. This material is arranged in alpha-numerical sequence at the end of the series under the folder grouping "Works of Art in Labeled Series." Other "BK" photographs are arranged alphabetially by folder title with assigned numbers indicated in parentheses. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  Series includes photographs of Drewes, including studio, portrait, family, exhibition and travel photographs. Also found are many photographs, negatives, and transparencies, as well as 8 glass negatives of works of art by Drewes. Many photographs of works of art have corresponding negatives affixed to the back of the photos.
  - Bauhaus Buildings, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Colleagues/Friends, circa 1960s-circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Exhibitions, 1940s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 23-31)
  - Exhibitions, "Harald's AAA Gallery Show and Some of Wolf's Colored Windows", circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Exhibitions, "Sixty-Five Years of Printmaking" (1985) (BK22) (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Family/Friends, circa 1890s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 34-35)
  - In Studio and Teaching, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Interiors of Drewes Home (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1980s-2000 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Point Pleasant and Wolfram Drewes House, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Portraits of Drewes and Maria Drewes, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Oversized material housed in box 17, Folder 6
  - Portraits of Drewes (BK7), 1980 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - School Photograph, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Travel (inc. Manhattan G18), circa 1960s-1977 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Travel: California and Colorado; Europe (Seconds); Guatemala, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Travel: Majorca, Spain; Mexico, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Travel: Peru; Yucatan, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Travel: Peru Documentation, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Travel: Photo Album-U.S.A. Trip, Buildings (BK6), 1926 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Works of Art, circa 1970s-circa 1990s (Box 11, Folder 3-32)
  - Works of Art, Negatives, circa 1970s-circa 1990s (Box 11, Folder 33-35)
  - Works of Art, Numbered 1-1500s, circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
  - Works of Art, Album, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Works of Art, Album, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Works of Art, Collection of C. & S. L. Osgood, circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Works of Art Given To C. U., 1992 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Works of Art, Slides, 1960s-circa 1990s (Box 12, Folder 12-23)
  - Works of Art, Slides by B. Kopp, 1970s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 24-29)
  - Works of Art, Slides by Marianne Gurley, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - Works of Art, Slides by Marianne Gurley, Extras, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3-7)
  - Works of Art, Slides of Work Bought by National Park Service, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
  - Works of Art, Slides "Steinberg Hall" (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Works of Art, Watercolors Returned from Snyder Gallery, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Works of Art, Wolfram Drewes Private Art Collection, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
  - Works of Art, Transparencies, 1970s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 14-16)
  - Works of Art in Labeled Series
    - BK2: Photo Positives of Artwork, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - BK3: Photo Positives of Artwork, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 18)
      Oversized material housed in Box 17, Folder 7
    - BK5: Photo Scrapbook, 1935-1953 (Box 13, Folder 19-21)
    - BK6: Photo Postivies of Rose Catalogue Artwork, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 22-23)
    - BK8: Photos of Woodcuts, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - BK9: Photos by Marianne Gurley for Book, circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - BK10: Sleeves of Glass Plate Negatives of Artwork, circa 1956 (Box 13, Folder 26)
      (8 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 2)
    - BK11: Photos of Early Paintings, Portraits, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - BK13: Photo Album of Black and White Photos of Artwork, circa 1930s (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - BK14: Photo Albums of Black and White Photos of Old "Rare" Pictures, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - BK15: Black and White Photos with Negatives of Artwork, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
    - BK16: Photos of Oils by Drewes, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - BK19: Black and White Photos of Artwork with Negatives, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - BK20: Black and White Photos of Artwork, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Oversized material housed in Box 17, Folder 8
    - BK23: Transparencies by Marianne Gurley, circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - BK24: Transparencies by Marianne Gurley, circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - BK25: Brigitte Helloth Material, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - BK26: Photos of Artwork, circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
    - BK27: Slide Box File of Paintings, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
    - BK27: Slide Box File of Paintings, Documentation from original box, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 8 Glass negatives (Box MGP 2)
  - Works of Art by Others, circa 1990s (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Works of Art by Others, Sold at Auction for Estate, circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Portraits of Drewes and Maria Drewes from Box 10, Folder 3 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Oversized BK3: Photo Positives of Artwork from Box 13, Folder 18 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Works of Art in Labeled Series BK 20: Black and White Photos of Artwork from Box 14, Folder 6 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Mary (Maria) Louise Lischer Drewes Papers, 1930s-1980s; Series 9; 1 Linear feet Box 15
  Papers provide scattered documentation of Maria Drewes' marriage to Werner Drewes and her career as a jewelry professor and desginer. Correspondence relating to her work prior to her marriage to Drewes, includes her 1957 teaching certificate and letters of reference from the City Art Museum of St. Louis, as well as family letters and diaries primarily documenting European travels during the 1960s-1980s. Also found are notes, a scrapbook and photographs of Maria Drewes' jewelry designs.
  - Correspondence, 1940s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Letters to Family, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
  - Death Notices, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Diaries, 1960-1986 (Box 15, Folder 5-9)
  - Insurance Valuation of Jewelry, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Marriage Announcements and Letters, 1950s, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Jewelry, 1930s-1940s (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
  - Scrapbook of Jewelry Designs, 1960s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook of Photographs of Jewelry, circa 1970s (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, 1930s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Photograph Album of Maria's Family, circa 1900-circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Jewelry, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 15, Folder 18-19)